A Guide to the Article Files of the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, ca. 1964-1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Article Files of the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia ca. 1964-1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-24/2/2.761
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was an archival transfer from the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia, November 29, 1976.
Scope and Content
Typescripts of articles submitted to the editors of Studies in Bibliography, the publication of the Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia.
Arrangement
The articles are arranged chronologically and subarranged alphabetically by the author's surname. They are preceded by the table of contents, if extant. Following the undated typescripts is a small group of minutes of the Bibliographical Society Council, miscellaneous notes on contributors, miscellaneous notes and typescripts, and three unpublished typescripts of articles.
Contents List
- Typescript of Light on Joyce's Exiles: A New Ms, A Curious Analogue, and Some Speculations by Robert M. Adams, 1964 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Typescript of James Kirke Paulding's Contribution to American Magazines by Ralph M. Aderman, 1964 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Typescript of The Terence of Turin, 1483 by Curt F. Bumlu;hler, 1964 (Box-folder 1:3)
- Typescript of Bound in Boston by Henry B. Legg by Hannah D. French, 1964 (Box-folder 1:4)
- Typescript of Milton and the Harvard Pindar by Maurice Kelley and Samuel D. Atkins, 1964 (Box-folder 1:5)
- Typescript of A Computer Concordance to Middle English Texts by Alan Markman, 1964 (Box-folder 1:6)
- Typescript of Yeat's Vision and The Two Trees by Robert Mortenson, 1964 (Box-folder 1:7)
- Typescript of The Early Editions of Sir Walter Ralegh's The History of the World by John Racin, Jr., 1964 (Box-folder 1:8)
- Typescript of Further Observations On the Text of Dubliners by Robert Scholes, 1964 (Box-folder 1:9)
- Typescript of Matthew Carey's Proofreaders by Rolo G. Silver, 1964 (Box-folder 1:10)
- Typescript of Unsigned and Initialed Contributions of The Freeman by G. Thomas Tanselle, 1964 (Box-folder 1:11)
- Typescript of The Printer of the 1594 Octavo of Marlowe's Edward II by Robert Ford Welsh, 1964 (Box-folder 1:12)
- Typescript of Predecessors to Burke's and Dodsley's Annual Register by John C. Weston, Jr., 1964 (Box-folder 1:13)
- Typescript of A Selective Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship for 1962, Part II, 1964 (Box-folder 1:14)
- Typescript of William Strahan's Ledgers, II: Charges for Paper, 1738-1785 by Patricia Hernlund, 1967 (Box-folder 1:15)
- Typescript of The Greatest English Lyric? A New Reading of Joe E. Skilmer's Therese by John Frederick Nims, 1967 (Box-folder 1:16)
- Typescript of pages from Studies in Bibliography, 1967 (Box-folder 1:17)
- Typescript of The Laureate as Huckster: Nahum Tate and an Early Eighteenth Century Example of Publisher's Advertising by Stuart L. Astor, 1968 (Box-folder 1:18)
- Typescript of Benson's Alleged Piracy of Shakespeare's Sonnets and of Some of Jonson's Works by Joesphine Waters Bennett, 1968 (Box-folder 1:19)
- Typescript of Gibbon's Revision of the Decline and Fall by Patricia B. Craddock, 1968 (Box-folder 1:20)
- Typescript of James Pinker to James Joyce, 1915-1920 by John Firth, 1968 (Box-folder 1:21)
- Typescript of William Gilmore Simms and the Southern Literary Gazette by John C. Guilds, 1968 (Box-folder 1:22)
- Typescript of Compositor B, the Parier Quartos, and Copy Spelling by William S. Kable, 1968 (Box-folder 1:23)
- Typescript of Eighteenth-Century Editions of Steel's Conscious Lovers by Shirley Strum Kenny, 1968 (Box-folder 1:24)
- Typescript of Speght's Chaucer and Ms GG. 4. 27 by George B. Pace, 1968 (Box-folder 1:25)
- Typescript of The Revisions of Richardson's Sir Charles Grandison by Robert Craig Pierson, 1968 (Box-folder 1:26)
- Typescript of Poe and Young America by Claude Richard, 1968 (Box-folder 1:27)
- Typescript of A Date and a Printer for A Looking Glasse for London and England by Berta Sturman, 1968 (Box-folder 2:1)
- Typescript of The Descriptive Bibliography of American Authors by G. Thomas Tanselle, 1968 (Box-folder 2:2)
- Typescript of James' Pandora: The Mixed Consequences of Revision by Charles Vandersee, 1968 (Box-folder 2:3)
- Typescript of Photo-Facsimiles of STC Books: A Cautionary Checklist by Franklin B. Williams, Jr., 1968 (Box-folder 2:4)
- Typescript of A Selective Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship for 1966, Part II, 1968 (Box-folder 2:5)
- Typescript of Table of Contents in Studies in Bibliography, 1969 (Box-folder 2:6)
- Typescript of Nineteenth-Century English Best-Sellers: A Further List by Richard D. Altick, 1969 (Box-folder 2:7)
- Typescript of The Meaning of Copy Text by Paul Baedner, 1969 (Box-folder 2:8)
- Typescript of Two Compositors in Heywood's Londons Ius Honorarium (1631) by David M. Bergeron, 1969 (Box-folder 2:9)
- Typescript of Scholarship and Mere Artifacts: The British Empire and Publication of Stephen Crane by Matthew I. Bruccoli and Joeseph Katz, 1969 (Box-folder 2:10)
- Typescript of Dates in Incunabular Colophons by Curt f. Bumlu;hler, 1969 (Box-folder 2:11)
- Typescript of Aphra Behn's First Biography by Robert Adams Day, 1969 (Box-folder 2:12)
- Typescript of The Lay of the Case by Philip Gaskell, 1969 (Box-folder 2:13)
- Typescript of Swinburne's Heptalogia Improved by Robert A. Greenberg, 1969 (Box-folder 2:14)
- Typescript of The Lost Number of the Southern Literary Gazette by John C. Guilds, 1969 (Box-folder 2:15)
- Typescript of The Printers and the Beaumont and Fletcher Folio of 1647, Sections 4 and 8D-F by Standish Henning, 1969 (Box-folder 2:16)
- Typescript of Ulysses Notebook VIII. A. 5 at Buffalo by Phillip F. Herring, 1969 (Box-folder 2:17)
- Typescript of The Oxford Old-Spelling Shakespeare Concordances by T. H. Howard-Hill, 1969 (Box-folder 2:18)
- Typescript of William Barley, Draper and Stationer by J. A. Lavin, 1969 (Box-folder 2:19)
- Typescript of Printers of the Mind: Some Notes on Bibliographical Theories and Printing-house Practices by D. F. McKenzie, 1969 (Box-folder 2:20)
- Typescript of The Text of Scott's Edition of Swift by Lee H. Potter, 1969 (Box-folder 2:21)
- Typescript of The Text of Keat's Ode on Indolence by Jack Stillinger, 1969 (Box-folder 2:22)
- Typescript of Copyright Records and the Bibliographer by G. Thomas Tanselle, 1969 (Box-folder 2:23)
- Typescript of The Order of Stanzas in Cowley and Crashaw's On Hope by George Walton Williams, 1969 (Box-folder 2:24)
- Typescript of A Selective Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship for 1967, Part II, 1969 (Box-folder 2:25)
- Typescript of Notes on Contributers in Studies in Bibliography, 1969 (Box-folder 2:26)
- Typescript of Table of Contents in Studies in Bibliography, 1970 (Box-folder 2:27)
- Typescript of John Nichols on a Johnson Letter by James L. Battersby, 1970 (Box-folder 2:28)
- Typescript of Notes on Early Editions of Fragmenta Aurea by L. A. Beaurline and Thomas Clayton, 1970 (Box-folder 2:29)
- Typescript of Chainlines versus Imposition in Incunabula by Curt Bumlu;hler, 1970 (Box-folder 2:30)
- Typescript of The Printing of Calderon's Tercera Parte by D. W. Cruikshank, 1970 (Box-folder 2:31)
- Typescript of The Compositors of the Cambridge Platfrom by John H. Dorenkamp, 1970 (Box-folder 3:1)
- Typescript of James Branch Cabell's Personal Library by Maurice Duke, 1970 (Box-folder 3:2)
- Typescript of Thomas Creede's Pica Roman by W. Craig Ferguson, 1970 (Box-folder 3:3)
- Typescript of The Bibliographical Significance of a Publisher's Archive: The Macmillan Papers by William E. Freedman, 1970 (Box-folder 3:4)
- Typescript of John Warburton's Lost Plays by John Freehafer, 1970 (Box-folder 3:5)
- Typescript of Pope as Scholar-Editor by John A. Hart, 1970 (Box-folder 3:6)
- Typescript of Defoe's An Essay Upon Projects: The Order of the Issues by Joyce Deveau Kennedy, 1970 (Box-folder 3:7)
- Typescript of John Danter's Ornament Stock by J. A. Lavin, 1970 (Box-folder 3:8)
- Typescript of Press Letters: Samual Aris, 1730-1732 by Keith I. D. Maslen, 1970 (Box-folder 3:9)
- Typescript of Four Children's Books by A. A. Milne by John R. Payne, 1970 (Box-folder 3:10)
- Typescript of Additions to Bond's Register of Burlesque Poems by A. J. Sambrook, 1970 (Box-folder 3:11)
- Typescript of The Orthography of Proper Names in Modern-Spelling Editions of Shakespeare by Jurgen Schafer, 1970 (Box-folder 3:12)
- Typescript of The '1584' Publication of Henry Constable's Diana Augmented by Hassel B. Sledd, 1970 (Box-folder 3:13)
- Typescript of The Bibliographical Descriptions of Patterns by G. Thomas Tanselle, 1970 (Box-folder 3:14)
- Typescript of The Meaning of Copy-Text: A Further Note by G. Thomas Tanselle, 1970 (Box-folder 3:15)
- Typescript of John Faulkner: An Annotated Check List of his Published Works and of His Papers by Helen White and Redding S. Sugg, Jr., 1970 (Box-folder 3:16)
- Typescript of Photo-Facsimiles of STC Books: A Sequel by Franklin B. Williams, Jr., 1970 (Box-folder 3:17)
- Typescript of More on the Contributors to the American Quarterly Review (1827-1837) by Guy R. Woodall, 1970 (Box-folder 3:18)
- Typescript of A Selective Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship for 1968, Part II, 1970 (Box-folder 3:19)
- Typescript of Notes on Contributors in Studies in Bibliography, 1970 (Box-folder 3:20)
- Typescript of Pages in Studies in Bibliography, 1970 (Box-folder 3:21)
- Typescript of Table of Contents in Studies in Bibliography, 1971 (Box-folder 3:22)
- Typescript of Pope in Russian Translations of the Eighteenth Century by Leonid M. Arinshtein, 1971 (Box-folder 3:23)
- Typescript of John Payne Collier's Great Forgery by Giles Dawson, 1971 (Box-folder 3:24)
- Typescript of The Printing of James Shirley's The Polititian (1655) by Robert J. Fehrenbach, 1971 (Box-folder 3:25)
- Typescript of Compositors in A King and No King Hans Walter Gabler, 1971 (Box-folder 3:26)
- Typescript of Cupids Revenge (Q1) and its Compositors by Hans Walter Gabler, 1971 (Box-folder 3:27)
- Typescript of Mechanized Textual Collation and Recent Designs by Gordon Lindstrand, 1971 (Box-folder 3:28)
- Typescript of Printing Chargers: Inference and Evidence by Keith I. D. Maslen, 1971 (Box-folder 3:29)
- Typescript of Bartleby the Scrivener and Melville's Contemporary Reputation by George Monteiro, 1971 (Box-folder 3:30)
- Typescript of Emerson's Annotations in the British Museum Copy of the Dial by Burton R. Pollin, 1971 (Box-folder 3:31)
- Typescript of William Gilmore Simms and the Family Companion by Robert A. Rees and Marjorie Griffin, 1971 (Box-folder 3:32)
- Typescript of The Composition and Revision of Coleridge's Essay on Aeschylus' Prometheus by S. W. Reid, 1971 (Box-folder 3:33)
- Typescript of John Oldmixon and An Impartial Enquiry (1715) by Pat Rogers, 1971 (Box-folder 3:34)
- Typescript of The Ralegh Group in The Phoenix Nest by Michael Rudick, 1971 (Box-folder 4:1)
- Typescript of Arthur Maynwaring, Richard Steele, and The Lives of Two Illustrious Generals by Henry L. Snyder, 1971 (Box-folder 4:2)
- Typescript of Woozles in Brontumle;land: A Cautionary Tale by Joan Stevens, 1971 (Box-folder 4:3)
- Typescript of Dating Whitman's Early Notebooks by Floyd Stovall, 1971 (Box-folder 4:4)
- Typescript of Description of Paper by G. Thomas Tanselle, 1971 (Box-folder 4:5)
- Typescript of A New Light on the Dramatic Works of Thomas Killigrew by Albert Wertheim, 1971 (Box-folder 4:6)
- Typescript of Some Sources of the Essays in Robert Walsh's Didactics by Guy Woodall, 1971 (Box-folder 4:7)
- Typescript of A Selective Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship for 1969, Part II, 1971 (Box-folder 4:8)
- Typescript of Notes on Contributors in Studies in Bibliography, 1971 (Box-folder 4:9)
- Typescript of Table of Contents in Studies in Bibliography, 1972 (Box-folder 4:10)
- Typescript of The Evidence from Defoe's Title Pages by Rodney M. Baine, 1972 (Box-folder 4:11)
- Typescript of David Douglas and the British Publication of W. D. Howells' Works by Scott Bennett, 1972 (Box-folder 4:12)
- Typescript of Science, Method, and the Textual Critic by Peter Davison, 1972 (Box-folder 4:13)
- Typescript of Thoreau Rejects An Emerson Text by Wendell Glick, 1972 (Box-folder 4:14)
- Typescript of Gilbert and His Ballads: Problems in the Bibliography and Attribution of Victorian Comic Journalism by John Bush Jones, 1972 (Box-folder 4:15)
- Typescript of Oscar Wilde's first manuscript of The Picture of Dorian Gray by Donald L. Lawler, 1972 (Box-folder 4:16)
- Typescript of Some Unusual Printer's Copy Used for Early Sixteenth-Century Editions of Erasmus' Encomium Moriae by Clarence H. Miller, 1972 (Box-folder 4:17)
- Typescript of Mather's Melville Book by George Monteiro, 1972 (Box-folder 4:18)
- Typescript of Index and Author Guide to the Family Companion (1841-1843) by Robert A. Rees and Marjorie Griffin, 1972 (Box-folder 4:19)
- Typescript of Shakespeare's Merchant of Venice in Sixty-three Editions by Christopher Spencer, 1972 (Box-folder 4:20)
- Typescript of Some Principles for Editorial Apparatus by G. Thomas Tanselle, 1972 (Box-folder 4:21)
- Typescript of The Westminster Review: Change of Editorship, 1804 by Rosemary T. Van Arsdel, 1972 (Box-folder 4:22)
- Typescript of A Selective Check List of Bibliographical Scholarship for 1970, Part II, 1972 (Box-folder 4:23)
- Typescript of Notes on Contributors in Studies in Bibliography, 1972 (Box-folder 4:24)
- Typescript of Pages in Studies in Bibliography, 1972 (Box-folder 4:25)
- Electrostatic copy of Volume XXV of Studies in Bibliography with missing pages and holograph corrections, 1972 (Box-folder 4:26)
- Electrostatic copy of Volume XXV of Studies in Bibliography with missing pages and holograph corrections, 1972 (Box-folder 5:1)
- Typescript of A Method for Compiling a Concordance for a Middle English Text by Sidney Berger, 1973 (Box-folder 5:2)
- Typescript of Marlowe's Doctor Faustus: The 1602 Additions by Fredson Bowers, 1973 (Box-folder 5:3)
- Typescript of Observations on the 1562 Editions of Cardinal Reginald Pole's De Concilio and Reformatio Angliae by Curt F. Bumlu;hler, 1973 (Box-folder 5:4)
- Typescript of Samuel Edgerley: Printer in Calabar, 1846-1857 by R. H. Carnie, 1973 (Box-folder 5:5)
- Typescript of Simmes' Compositor and Five Shakespeare Quartos by Allan E. Craven, 1973 (Box-folder 5:6)
- Typescript of The Compositors of Shakespeare's Folio Comedies by T. H. Howard-Hill, 1973 (Box-folder 5:7)
- Typescript of Annotations by Coleridge in A Copy of The Friend (1818) by Peter Mann, 1973 (Box-folder 5:8)
- Typescript of Periodical Literature of English and American Bibliography by G. Thomas Tanselle, 1973 (Box-folder 5:9)
- Typescript of The Plots of The Dead Man's Fortune and 2 Seven Deadly Sins: Inferences for Theatre Historians by Scott McMillin, 1973 (Box-folder 5:10)
- Typescript of An Annotated List of Contributions to the Boston Dial by Joel Myerson, 1973 (Box-folder 5:11)
- Typescript of A Bibliographic History of Alfred Tennyson's Idylls of the King by John Pfordresher, 1973 (Box-folder 5:12)
- Typescript of On the Use of the Verb Facere in Early Colophons by Dennis E. Rhodes, 1973 (Box-folder 5:13)
- Typescript of Dating Through Calligraphy: The Example of Dover Beach by S. O. A. Ullmann, 1973 (Box-folder 5:14)
- Typescript of Richardson's Revisions of Clarissa in the Second Edition by Shirley Van Marter, 1973 (Box-folder 5:15)
- Typescript of The Corrections Lists for F. Scott Fitzgerald's This Side of Paradise by James L. W. West, III, 1973 (Box-folder 5:16)
- Typescript of Lower-case 2-r in 16th Century English Black Letter Texts by Melvin H. Wolf, 1973 (Box-folder 5:17)
- Typescript of Table of Contents in Studies in Bibliography, 1973 (Box-folder 5:18)
- Typescript of Notes on Contributors in Studies in Bibliography, 1973 (Box-folder 5:19)
- Typescript of Proofreading of The Revenge of Bussy D'Ambois by R. J. Lordi, n.d. (Box-folder 5:20)
- Typescript of A Midsummernight's Dream- or a Textual Scholar's Nightmare! by G. S. McCaughey, n.d. (Box-folder 5:21)
- Typescript of Conrad's Revisions of The Secret Agent by Marion C. Michael, n.d. (Box-folder 5:22)
- Typescript of Notes on Contributors in Studies in Bibliography, ca. 1914-1973 (Box-folder 6:1)
- Miscellaneous Notes and Typescripts, n.d., 2 folders. (Box-folder 6:2)
- Miscellaneous Papers, n.d. (Box-folder 6:3)